<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Faq xmlns="http://content.mpass.airnz.com/faq/1/0">
	<Categories>
		<Category>
			<Name>Airpoints and Koru</Name>
			<Type>Airpoints</Type>
			<Questions>
				<Question>
					<QuestionText>How many guests can I bring into Koru or International Lounges?</QuestionText>
					<AnswerText>
						<p>Koru members are welcome to bring 1 guest to our lounges prior to the departure of your Air New Zealand flight. Like you, your guest needs to be departing on an Air New Zealand ticketed and operated flight from that airport that day. Guest access is subject to space being available and may not be available at some of our partner lounges overseas. Children under the age of 12 travelling with you are welcome in Air New Zealand operated lounges for free.</p>
						<p>Koru members travelling with more friends may be able to purchase lounge passes to use on the day at the lounge subject to availability. Alternatively you can purchase an annual guest card to supplement your guest entitlement throughout the year which can be purchased through the Koru contact centre or at the lounge.</p>
						<p>Gold and Gold Elite Airpoints members may also bring 1 guest into Air New Zealand lounges, subject to space. Gold Elite Airpoints members enjoy the benefit of bringing up to 5 guests into Air New Zealand lounges (subject to space) and 1 guest into regional or Star Alliance lounges.</p>
					</AnswerText>
				</Question>
				<Question>
					<QuestionText>Who is entitled to use Koru or International Lounges?</QuestionText>
					<AnswerText>
						<p>Air New Zealand operated Koru and International lounges may be used by Air New Zealand Koru members who are travelling on an Air New Zealand ticketed and operated flight the same day. From time to time at our Los Angeles lounge Koru members may be accommodated in an alternative lounge. Unfortunately Koru members in transit on NZ1 or NZ2 to or from London can not be accommodated at the Los Angeles lounge.</p>
						<p>Silver Airpoints members may use one of their complimentary one-entry lounge passes for all Koru lounges in New Zealand and all Air New Zealand operated International Lounges when travelling on an Air New Zealand ticketed and operated flight the same day. Please present your Silver lounge pass to a lounge concierge (or at checkin for regional lounges).</p>
						<p>Gold and Gold Elite Airpoints members have access to all Koru lounges in New Zealand and all Air New Zealand operated International Lounges. You also have access to Star Alliance Gold Lounges worldwide. Access to United Red Carpet Clubs, US Airways Clubs and US Airways Envoy Lounges in the USA is only available when presenting a boarding pass in conjunction with international travel. Simply present your Gold or Gold Elite membership card along with your same-day Air New Zealand or Star Alliance boarding pass at the lounge reception.</p>
					</AnswerText>
				</Question>
				<Question>
					<QuestionText>What do I do if I do not know my Airpoints Number?</QuestionText>
					<AnswerText>
						<p>You will need to call the Air New Zealand Contact Centre on 0800 247 764 (for New Zealand), 1800 803 298 (Australia) or +64 9 357 3000 from other countries.</p>
					</AnswerText>
				</Question>
			</Questions>
		</Category>
		<Category>
			<Name>My Booking</Name>
			<Type>Booking</Type>
			<Questions>
				<Question>
					<QuestionText>Which seats can Airpoints Gold, Gold Elite and Koru members choose on their flights?</QuestionText>
					<AnswerText>
						<p>If you are an Airpoints Gold, Gold Elite or Koru member you can request seats in the Premium Seating areas of our aircraft. Your Airpoints membership number must be entered in your confirmed booking before you can request a seat.</p>
						<p>When travelling on a Tasman or Pacific flight, Airpoints Gold, Gold Elite or Koru members can select seats in the Premium Seating (Space+) area for themselves and all other travellers on the same booking, provided the Gold, Gold Elite or Koru member has booked The Works. Any other travellers on the booking may be booked on Seat, Seat+Bag or The Works fares.</p>
					</AnswerText>
				</Question>
				<Question>
					<QuestionText>Can I change or cancel my Domestic and/or Tasman and Pacific Island booking?</QuestionText>
					<AnswerText>
						<p>You can change or cancel your domestic and/or Tasman and Pacific Island booking online through our Manage Booking facility, if you change your booking online, no service fee will apply. You are able to change or cancel based on the fare you have paid for and you won't need to pay another credit card fee. For Tasman and Pacific Island bookings, you are able to request a ticket copy, upgrade your ticket, cancel your booking or add your passport details online.</p>
						<p>If you purchased travel insurance at the time of your booking, your insurance will be transferred so that you are covered for your updated itinerary.</p>
						<p>Domestic - Service charges may apply</p>
						<p>Domestic grabaseat™ and Smart Saver fares may be changed before the day of departure. This will be subject to the payment of a change fee and any extra fare amount should the current fare level no longer be available.</p>
						<p>Flexi Plus fares are free to change at the airport on the day of travel. Other changes may be made up to departure subject to payment of any extra fare amount should the current fare level no longer be available. These fares can also be held in credit for up to 12 months.</p>
						<p>The fare rules of your new ticket will apply, with the exception of cancellation rules. For example, you cannot change to a Flexi ticket then subsequently cancel the booking for a full refund.</p>
						<p>Tasman and Pacific - Service charges may apply</p>
						<p>Tasman and Pacific Smart Saver, Flexi Saver and Business Saver fares may be changed up until departure. This will be subject to the payment of a change fee and service fee and any extra fare amount should the current fare level no longer be available.</p>
						<p>Flexi and Business Class fares may be changed up to departure, subject to payment of a service fee and any extra fare amount should the current fare level no longer be available. These fares can also be held in credit for up to 12 months.</p>
					</AnswerText>
				</Question>
			</Questions>
		</Category>
		<Category>
			<Name>Check-in</Name>
			<Type>Checkin</Type>
			<Questions>
				<Question>
					<QuestionText>What do I need to check-in for my international flight?</QuestionText>
					<AnswerText>
						<p>To check-in for an international flight you need your passport and any other documentation (such as a visa) pertaining to your passport nationality, destination and any transit countries. Also bring a copy of your Electronic Ticket, or paper ticket if you have been given one.</p>
						<p>If travelling to or via the USA, and entering under the Visa Waiver Program, you must have applied for an ESTA travel authorisation at least 72 hours before departure. When granted, an ESTA remains valid against the registered passport number for 2 years. You must also know the address where you are staying in the USA.</p>
					</AnswerText>
				</Question>
				<Question>
					<QuestionText>What identification checks take place at self-service ExpressCheck kiosks?</QuestionText>
					<AnswerText>
						<p>To use a kiosk you need to insert a form of ID - your Airpoints or Koru card, Star Alliance frequent flyer card, or credit/debit card.</p>
					</AnswerText>
				</Question>
				<Question>
					<QuestionText>Can I check-in online?</QuestionText>
					<AnswerText>
						<p>Air New Zealand does not offer online check-in.</p>
						<p>For check-in at the airport we offer:</p>
						<p>Domestic - check-in no later than 30 minutes prior to departure:</p>
						<p>Go straight to the gate with your ETicket, mPass or ePass. If you have baggage or queries, you can check-in at the kiosk in the domestic terminals throughout New Zealand. If you are connecting to an international flight, please check-in 60 minutes prior to your flight. If you are travelling from Christchurch to Auckland on flights NZ37, NZ90 and NZ98 you will need to check-in at least 60 minutes prior to departure at the International terminal at Christchurch airport.</p>
						<p>International - check-in no later than 90 minutes prior to departure.</p>
						<p>For travellers to Australia you can check in at the Kiosks at the International Terminal in Auckland using your ETicket or mPass or ePass PLUS your machine readable passport no later than 90 mintes prior to departure.</p>
						<p>For other international destinations, you can use your ETicket at the check-in counters.</p>
					</AnswerText>
				</Question>
			</Questions>
		</Category>
		<Category>
			<Name>Flight Information</Name>
			<Type>Flights</Type>
			<Questions>				
				<Question>
					<QuestionText>I left an item on the plane or in the lounge. Who should I contact?</QuestionText>
					<AnswerText>
						<p>If you have misplaced an item either onboard one of our flights or in one of our lounges, please contact our local Baggage Services office to report the details of your loss.</p>
					</AnswerText>
				</Question>
				<Question>
					<QuestionText>What are excess baggage charges for domestic flights?</QuestionText>
					<AnswerText>
						<p>For domestic flights throughout New Zealand you can have one piece of baggage carried for free if you have purchased a product that includes a bag. The first additional piece is $30, second additional piece is $75 (e.g. $105 for two additional pieces), the third additional piece is $150.</p>
					</AnswerText>
				</Question>
				<Question>
					<QuestionText>What happens if I no-show for my flight?</QuestionText>
					<AnswerText>
						<p>If you are travelling on a Domestic grabaseat™, Smart Saver or Pacific Smart Saver fare, the fare becomes non-changeable on the day of departure. If you miss your flight you will be required to purchase a new one way fare.</p>
						<p>If your plans change or you can’t make your flight, please do your best to call us on 0800 737 000 (for New Zealand) or +64 9 357 3000 from other countries (a change fee and service fee may be applicable).</p>
					</AnswerText>
				</Question>
				<Question>
					<QuestionText>What happens if my flight has been cancelled because of bad weather?</QuestionText>
					<AnswerText>
						<p>Air New Zealand can advise you of any changes in your flight schedule when you use TextExpress. All you need to do is text your flight number (for example NZ405) to 737 and we will text you back with latest flight departure and arrival information for that flight.</p>
						<p>You can also check the status of your <a href="http://m.airnz.co.nz/flightinfo/">flight online</a>. Just select the arrival or departure city of your flight and select Go to check if your flight is arriving or departing on time.</p>
						<p>Air New Zealand staff at the airport or the Contact Centre (phone 0800 737 000) will rebook you on the next available flight, weather permitting.</p>
					</AnswerText>
				</Question>
				<Question>
					<QuestionText>Where can I get information on Air New Zealand's flight schedules, and the destinations that you fly to and from?</QuestionText>
					<AnswerText>
						<p>For arrival and departure information, <a href="http://m.airnz.co.nz/flightinfo/">click here</a> (internet access required).</p>
						<p>For Flight timetables, <a href="http://airnz.travelsked.com/pdaSchedules.asp?custcode=NZ">go here.</a></p> 
					</AnswerText>
				</Question>
			</Questions>
		</Category>
		<Category>
			<Name>Terms and Conditions</Name>
			<Type>Other</Type>
			<Questions>
				<Question>
					<QuestionText>Terms and Conditions</QuestionText>
					<AnswerText>
						<p><a href="http://www.airnewzealand.co.nz/mpass-terms-and-conditions">Terms and Conditions</a></p>
					</AnswerText>
				</Question>
			</Questions>
		</Category>
	</Categories>
</Faq>
